

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

(+1) 407-601.9438 victorteppa@gmail.com Kissimmee, FL. 34744 https://vteppaweb.github.io/resume/index.html

## **Professional Summary**

I am a web designer and developer with over 8 years of overseas creativity and passionate experience with a high level of academic education based on my bachelor degree in computer science in Venezuela.

Determination to learn new technologies, proactive attitude, written and verbal communication are just some of my key strengths, which will make me a very competitive candidate.

Others key strengths that I possess include, but are not limited to, the following:

- My knowledge on life cycle development software.
- I am a self-starter and an excellent team worker.
- Knowledge of SEO and UI/UX design.
- Responsive web application design.
- My passion and ability to create apps and website solutions.
- Front End and Back End Programming Experience.
- Always willing to learn and stay tune with the latest technologies.

It would be great to have the opportunity that allow me to have a professional development and continue my career in this wonderful field.

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

## **Experience**

#### **Front End Web Developer**

GeoSnapShot
<a href="http://www.geosnapshot.com">http://www.geosnapshot.com</a>
Sydney, Australia.
Sep, 2015 – Sep, 2017.

- Maintenance of the web pages look & feel.
- Evaluation of new changes under new web templates.
- Create responsive HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript web templates.
- Work on changes using (GIT-HUB, BOOTSTRAP, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, Sublime Text Editor).

# **Web Application Developer**

MS21Consulting. Venezuela. April 2012 – Jan, 2013. DIRECTV Venezuela – Latin America & Caribbean (Satellite TV Company).

http://www.directv.com.ve/.

- Maintenance of the desktop, web applications, web services and windows services implemented.
- Analyse, design and development of new web applications.
- Responsible for the development of Front End and Back End of the project.
- Languages: HTML, CSS, C#. NET, JavaScript, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, SQL Server.
- Architectures: SOA and 3-Tier.

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

## **Analysts & Web Developer App**

NewTech Sistemas, C.A. Venezuela. Nov, 2009 – March, 2012. 3M Manufacturing Company - Venezuela. http://www.3m.com.ve/.

- Design and development of an application to supervise and monitoring the products samples of the sales department of multinational 3M Manufacture Company.
- Design, development and implementation of a web application store of 3M products under intranet.
- Languages: HTML, CSS, VB.NET, C# NET, JavaScript, CSS, XML, ADO.NET and ASP.NET.
- Database: Microsoft SQL Server 2005 2008, I-Series IBM AS/400.
- **Software:** IBM I-Series AS/400, Microsoft Internet Explorer 7-8, Mozilla Firefox 4.0, Microsoft Office Suite, IBM Lotus Notes 8.5, Macromedia Dreamweaver, Adobe Photoshop, Visual Studio.Net 2003/2010, Microsoft Project, Reporting Services 2007, OlikView 9.0, Cisco IP Communicator.

#### **Web Application Developer**

Grupo SMS, C.A. Venezuela. July, 2007 – Oct, 2009. Movilnet / Movistar (mobile telecommunication companies). <a href="http://www.movistar.com.ve/">http://www.movistar.com.ve/</a>.

- Design and Development of new web applications. The most important projects developed using this programs were:
  - Creation of a Microsoft SharePoint web application to supervise and monitoring the workflow of the process of all departments of the multinational company: Movistar – Telefonica Venezuela. Project duration: 10 months.
  - 2. Collaboration in the design and development of the Look & Feel of web applications.



**Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science** 

- **Programming Languages**: HTML, XHTML XSLT Transformations, VB.NET, C#.NET, JavaScript, CSS, XML, ASP.NET, CAML, Flex Builder 3.0 and Action Script 2.0.
- **Database:** Microsoft SQL Server 2008.
- **Software:** Internet Explorer 6-7, Mozilla Firefox, Microsoft Office, Macromedia Dreamweaver, Adobe Photoshop, Visual Studio.Net 2005, Microsoft Project, Microsoft Reporting Services 2005, Microsoft SQL Server 2005, Microsoft SharePoint Server and SharePoint Designer 2007.
- **Architectures:** 3-Tier, MVC and SOA.

## **Multimedia eLearning Developer**

The eLearning Solutions, C.A. Venezuela. Sep, 2005 – May, 2007.

- Collaborate with the creative illustrator and design department.
- Develop the learning platform with the supplied files and tools using Macromedia Flash and coding all characters movements.
- Work in the design and development of the Look & Feel in all projects.

**Languages**: Action Script 2.0.

Software: Microsoft Office Suite 97/2000/2003, Macromedia Flash MX, Adobe

Photoshop, Premiere and After Effects.

**Venezuelan – Bachelor Degree in Computing Science** 

#### **Education:**

Nueva Esparta University.

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science. www.une.edu.ve Caracas - Venezuela May 2006.

### **Courses & Seminaries:**

Coursera.org by UCDAVIS University of California.

SEO - Search Engine Optimization.

www.coursera.org

SEO Optimization / Fundamentals / Best Practices / Advanced Content and Social Tactics to Optimize SEO / Optimizing a Website for Search.

December, 2020.

Coursera.org by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.

Front End Web UI Frameworks and Tools.

www.coursera.org

Bootstrap, Angular, NodeJs, MongoDB, JQuery, NPM, Lite-Server, Json, Github, CSS Pre-processors Less and Sass. September, 2020 – November, 2020.

Coursera Project Network.

Position Elements on a Page with CSS. www.coursera.org HTML5, CSS3. November, 2020.

Coursera.org by University of Michigan.

Web Design, Development and Coding. www.coursera.org HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap and Advanced Responsive Design. August, 2020 – September, 2020.

TAFE Ultimo, New South Wales.

Web Design & Development (Certificate III and IV). www.tafensw.edu.au/tafe-nsw Sydney, Australia. July, 2014 – May, 2015

Navitas English Institute.

Academic English level 2 and 3. www.navitasenglish.edu.au Sydney, Australia. February, 2014 – July, 2014

**Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science** 

# Navitas English Institute.

IELTS Preparation Course. www.navitasenglish.edu.au Sydney, Australia. September, 2013 - November, 2013

#### Navitas English Institute.

General English Course. www.navitasenglish.edu.au Brisbane, Australia. July, 2013 – September, 2013

# Navitas English Institute.

FCE – Cambridge First Certificate English. www.navitasenglish.edu.au Brisbane, Australia. March, 2013 – June, 2013

# Centro Integral de Comunicación Visual.

Adobe After Effects 7.0 Pro www.comunicacionvisual.com
This course was instructed by an approved member of the Adobe Authorized Training Provider in Venezuela.

2006.

# Centro Integral de Comunicación Visual.

Macromedia Fireworks MX 2004 www.comunicacionvisual.com This course was instructed by a fully-accredited member of the Macromedia Authorized Training Partner in Venezuela. 2004.

### Centro Integral de Comunicación Visual.

Adobe Flash MX 2004 Advanced Development (Action Script). www.comunicacionvisual.com
This course was instructed by a fully-accredited member of the Macromedia Authorized Training Partner in Venezuela.
2003.

#### CASE Institute.

Web Design. Caracas - Venezuela 2001.

### Instituto de Capacitación Técnica KEYS.

Networks Seminary. www.keysca.com Caracas - Venezuela 2000.

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

Luisa Cáceres de Arismendi Institute.

Technical repair and maintenance of personal computers. www.linkedin.com/company/itelca-instituto Caracas - Venezuela 1997.

#### **Professional Skills:**

- Life Cycle of Web Applications.
- Advanced Responsive Web Design (mobile first).
- SEO Search Engine Optimization.
- Front End Web UI / UX Frameworks.
- Ability to develop front end web sites from scratch using HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap4, Angular.
- Version control systems GitHub / BitBucket.
- Databases SQL-Server 2000/05/08.
- Back End programming using Visual Studio .NET, Web Forms, Master Pages, ASP.NET Web Controls, C#.NET, VB.NET
- CMS Content Management Systems: DNN / WordPress / Sitecore / Microsoft SharePoint Designer.
- LMS Learning Management Systems Experience (eLearning).
- Adobe & Macromedia Suite: Dreamweaver / Fireworks / Photoshop / After Effects / Flash.
- Basic Graphic Design & Video Editing.

# **Personal Skills:**

- Bilingual: English / Spanish.
- Multicultural and Open Minded.
- CPR and First Aid Certification.
- Passion for Fitness and Personal Trainer Certifications.
- Culinary Skills.